## Los Angeles, CA dom4822@yahoo.com

# Denzal Martin Full-Stack Developer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/denzalmartin-a7ab63104 https://dmartin.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/dmartin4820

Full-stack developer with a teaching background in physics at Stanford. Currently working towards a coding certificate in web development through the University of California, Berkeley Coding Bootcamp where JavaScript, HTML, Node.js, and MySQL were used for various projects. While teaching at Stanford, I engaged with students by walking through physics problems during office hours and during lab experiments each week. During the coding bootcamp, I worked on three projects of at least two other peers where teamwork, communication, and teaching were commonly invoked skills. Step-by-step testing and learning the concepts involved was my approach to solving challenging problems.

#### **PROJECTS**

Event Architect, University of California, Berkeley Extension Coding Bootcamp

Aug 2021

• Created an app that was intended to allow a user to view public/private events that other members created. Once a member, the user has the ability to create events and edit todo list items for that event. Technologies used: Handlebars, Node.js, JavaScript, Express.js, Heroku, Git, MySQL, Insomnia, Sequelize, Fetch API

Jam Map, University of California, Berkeley Extension Coding Bootcamp

Teaching Assistant, PHYSICS 24: Electricity, Magnetism, and Optics Lab

**July 2021** 

Winter 2021

• Devloped front-end JavaScript to call iTunes' and GetSongBPM's API for generating a list of music that meets user selected criteria. Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Fetch API

#### SKILLS

Programming/Scripting Soft Skills

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, MySQL, MVC, Express.js, Handlebars, Python Teaching, Teamwork, Communication, Problem-Solving, Project Management

#### **TEACHING**

Stanford University	Stanford, CA
Teaching assistant, PHYSICS 21: Mechanics, Fluids, Heat Stanford University	<b>Fall 2020</b> Stanford, CA
Teaching assistant, PHYSICS 24: Electricity Magnetism Lab Stanford University	<b>Spring 2020</b> Stanford, CA
Teaching assistant, PHYSICS 46: Light Heat Lab Stanford University	<b>Fall 2019</b> Stanford, CA
Teaching assistant, PHYSICS 26: Modern Physics Lab Stanford University	<b>Spring 2019</b> Stanford, CA

### EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant Mar. 2019 — June 2021

Stanford University, Prof. Giorgio Gratta Research Group

Stanford, CA

Analyzed rotational and librational motion of optically levitated microsphere using Fourier and Hilbert transforms with Scipy.
 Adapted FPGA code in LabView to dampen the librational degree of freedom by >1 order of magnitude. Designed tank circuit to reduce unwanted noise and signals in rotational spectra

Research Student Oct 2015 — May 2018

University of California, Merced, Prof. Sayantani Ghosh Research Group

Merced, CA

• Used LabView to perform 2-D spectroscopy scan of Mn doped ZnSe quantum dots. Created LabView program to control magnet and read data for Hanle effect measurement. Presented to peers and professors in MACES fellowship meetings.

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate, Coding Bootcamp University of California, Berkeley Extension Master of Science, Physics Stanford University

June 2021 — Sept 2021 Aug. 2018 — June 2021

Performed more than 2.5 years of studies in Ph.D program before withdrawing